{
    "problem1": {
        "question": "Consider the inviscid, incompressible flow of air along a streamline...",
        "answer": {
            "code": "\n                import numpy as np\n\n                P1 = 2116 # Pressure2 (lb/ft^2)\n                rho = 0.002377 # Density (slug/ft^3)\n                V1 = 10 # Velocity1 (ft/s)\n                V2 = 190 # Velocity2 (ft/s)\n\n                P2 = P1 + (1/2)*rho*V1**2 - (1/2)*rho*V2**2\n                print(\"Pressure at point 2:\", P2, \"lb/ft^2\")\n                ",
            "explanation": "This code uses Bernoulli\u2019s equation...",
            "references": [
                "John D. Anderson, Christopher P. Cadou (2024) Fundamentals of Aerodynamics, McGraw-Hill."
            ]
        }
    },
    "problem2": {
        "question": "Consider a cylindrical mixing tank with one outlet and two inlets with uniform radius...",
        "answer": {
            "code": "\n                import numpy as np\n\n                rho1 = 600 # Density1 (kg/m^2)\n                rho2 = 800 # Density2 (kg/m^2)\n                v1 = 2.7 # Velocity1 (m/s)\n                v2 = 1.6 # Velocity2 (m/s)\n                R = 0.02 # Radius (m)\n                L = 0.05 # Length (m)\n                A = 3.14159*R*L\n\n                mdot1 = rho1*A*v1\n                mdot2 = rho2*A*v2\n                mdot3 = mdot1 + mdot2\n\n                v3 = v1 + v2\n                rho3 = mdot3/(A*v3)\n\n                print(\"Mass density at the outlet:\", rho3, \"kg/m^2\")\n                ",
            "explanation": "We used volumetric flow rate Q = a*v because liquids have the property...",
            "references": [
                "https://phys.libretexts.org/Bookshelves/University_Physics/Physics_(Boundless)/10%3A_Fluids/10.5%3A_Fluids_in_Motion"
            ]
        }
    },
    "problem3": {
        "question": "Based on Bernoulli\u2019s equation, what are some forms of energy in a fluid? (Note that these forms are conservative, unlike heat transfer and other dissipative forms not included in Bernoulli\u2019s equation.)",
        "answer": "Kinetic energy due to velocity, and the work done by a pressure difference.",
        "references": [
            "https://openstax.org/books/university-physics-volume-1/pages/14-conceptual-questions"
        ]
    },
    "problem4": {
        "question": "What is the difference between a control volume and a system?",
        "answer": "A system refers to a fixed mass with a boundary. However, with time the boundary of the system may change, but the mass remains the same. Instead of focusing on a fixed mass, we can observe the flow through a window, this window is called a control volume.",
        "references": [
            "http://www-mdp.eng.cam.ac.uk/web/library/"
        ]
    },
    "problem5": {
        "question": "How does steady flow differ from unsteady flow?",
        "answer": "In steady flow, the conditions (such as velocity, pressure, and cross-section) can vary from point to point within the fluid, but they do not change over time. While in unsteady flow the fluid conditions change with time, for example water distribution systems during valve opening or closing."
    },
    "problem6": {
        "question": "A rigid tank contains a hot fluid that is cooled while being stirred by a paddle wheel. First, the internal energy of the fluid is 800 kJ. The fluid loses 500 kJ of heat, and the paddle wheel does 100 kJ of work on the fluid. Determine the final internal energy of the fluid disregarding the energy of the paddle wheel.",
        "answer": {
            "code": "\n                import numpy as np\n\n                W = 100 # shaft work (kJ)\n                Qout = 500 # heat lost from the fluid (kJ)\n                U1 = 800 # initial internal energy (kJ)\n\n                U2 = W - Qout + U1\n\n                print(\"The final internal energy of the system is\", U2, \"kJ\")\n                ",
            "explanation": "The tank is called rigid, and the system is stationary because it does not have any changes in their velocity or elevation during a process.",
            "references": [
                "Michael A. Boles, Yunus A \u00c7engel, (2024) Thermodynamics: An Engineering Approach, McGraw-Hill."
            ]
        }
    },
    "problem7": {
        "question": "Consider steady heat transfer through a 5-m \u00d7 7-m brick wall of a house that is 30 cm thick. On a day outside temperature is 0\u00b0C, inside the house the temperature is 27\u00b0C. The temperatures of the inner and outer surfaces of the brick wall are measured to be 20\u00b0C and 5\u00b0C. The rate of heat transfer through the wall is 1035 W. Determine the rate of entropy generation in the wall.",
        "answer": {
            "code": "\n                import numpy as np\n\n                Qdot = 1035 # rate of heat transfer (Watts)\n                T1 = 293 # temperature on outer surface (Kelvins)\n                T2 = 278 # temperature on inner surface (Kelvins)\n\n                Sdotin = Qdot / T1\n                Sdotout = Qdot / T2\n                Sgen = -1 * Sdotin + Sdotout\n\n                print(\"Therefore, the rate of entropy generation in the wall is\", Sgen, \"W/K\")\n                ",
            "explanation": "The entropy change of the wall is zero during this process because the heat and entropy enter from one side and leave from the other and inside the wall, there is no change.",
            "references": [
                "Michael A. Boles, Yunus A \u00c7engel, (2024) Thermodynamics: An Engineering Approach, McGraw-Hill."
            ]
        }
    },
    "problem8": {
        "question": "What is the change in entropy in an adiabatic process? Does this imply that adiabatic processes are reversible?",
        "answer": "An adiabatic process occurs without transferring heat or mass between the system and its environment and only transfers energy as work. In a reversible adiabatic process, the entropy change is zero but in an irreversible adiabatic process the entropy increases. So, this does not necessarily imply reversibility.",
        "reference": [
            "https://www.britannica.com/science/adiabatic-process"
        ]
    },
    "problem9": {
        "question": "Are the following scenarios reversible or irreversible? A) getting into a pool slowly B) jumping into a pool (from the perspective of water) C) a balloon deflating",
        "answer": "A is a reversible process because when you go into a pool slowly the water level rises slowly and maintains equilibrium and if you slowly get out the pool water will go back to normal. B is irreversible because by jumping into a pool, the water experiences sudden turbulence and waves cannot be reversed. C is reversible since balloons typically deflate slowly and unless the plastic is overly stretched, inflating a balloon would put it back to its original state."
    },
    "problem10": {
        "question": "A real process may be nearly adiabatic if it occurs over a very short time. How does the short time span help the process to be adiabatic?",
        "answer": "The short time span helps the process because the heat does not take enough time to enter the system and the transmission of heat from the surroundings takes time, so if the changes of the system occur suddenly, then there may not be enough time for the transmission of heat.",
        "references": [
            "https://courses.lumenlearning.com/suny-physics/chapter/15-2-the-first-law-of-thermodynamics-and-some-simple-processes/"
        ]
    },
    "problem11": {
        "question": "Consider a normal shock wave in a supersonic airstream where the pressure upstream of the shock is 1 atm. Calculate the loss of total pressure across the shock wave when the upstream Mach number is (a) M1 = 2, and (b) M1 = 4.",
        "answer": {
            "code": "\n                import numpy as np\n\n                # We can obtain upstream total pressure using p01 = (p01/p1)*p1 using the ratio corresponding with M1=2 from the isentropic flow tables\n                P1 = 1 # upstream pressure (atm)\n                P01overP1 = 7.824\n                P01 = P01overP1 * P1 # (atm)\n\n                # To get total pressure behind normal shock we use p02 = (p02/p01)*p01 again using M1 = 2 from the normal shock tables\n                P02overP01 = 0.7209\n                P02 = P02overP01 * P01 # (atm)\n\n                # The loss of total pressure for a\n                aloss = P01 - P02 # (atm)\n\n                # For M1 = 4 and we follow the same process again\n                P01onP1 = 151.8\n                P0_1 = P01onP1 * P1 # (atm)\n                P02onP01 = 0.1388\n                P0_2 = P02onP01 * P0_1 # (atm)\n                bloss = P0_1 - P0_2 # (atm)\n\n                print(\"The loss of total pressure for part a\", aloss, \"atm\")\n                print(\"The loss of total pressure for part b\", bloss, \"atm\")\n                ",
            "explanation": "The values used to get the ratio values are found in Appendix A and then Appendix B",
            "references": [
                "John D. Anderson, Christopher P. Cadou (2024) Fundamentals of Aerodynamics, McGraw-Hill."
            ]
        }
    },
    "problem12": {
        "question": "Consider an oblique shock wave with a wave angle of 30 degrees. The upstream flow Mach number is 2.4. Calculate the Mach number behind the wave.",
        "answer": {
            "code": "\n                import numpy as np\n                import math\n\n                # Using the wave angle, theta, and Mach number graph in figure 9.9 we get theta to be 6.5 degrees\n                theta = 6.5 # (degrees)\n                beta = 30 # (degrees)\n\n                # Also, we can find M1\u2019s normal component to be 1.2 giving the normal Mach number behind the wave\n                Mn2 = 0.8422\n                dif = beta - theta\n                den = math.sin(math.radians(dif))\n                M2 = Mn2 / den\n\n                print(\"The Mach number is\", M2, \"behind the wave\")\n                ",
            "explanation": "Mn2 is the normal Mach number behind the shock wave. The downstream Mach number itself, M2, needed to be found using the geometry displayed here.",
            "references": [
                "John D. Anderson, Christopher P. Cadou (2024) Fundamentals of Aerodynamics, McGraw-Hill."
            ]
        }
    },
    "problem13": {
        "question": "A supersonic flow with M1 = 1.5, p1 = 1 atm, and T1 = 288 K is expanded around a sharp corner (see Figure 9.26) through a deflection angle, theta, of 15 degrees. Calculate M2, p2, T2, p02, and T02.",
        "answer": {
            "code": "\n                import numpy as np\n\n                P1 = 1 # (atm)\n                T1 = 288 # (Kelvins)\n\n                # Looking at appendix C we get that M1 = 1.5 has nu1 = 11.91 degrees and we can use nu1 + theta = nu2 which is 26.91 degrees. And the corresponding Mach number for that is M2 = 2\n                # Using appendix A for M1 = 1.5 we get the following ratios\n                P01overP1 = 3.671\n                T01overT1 = 1.45\n\n                # And for M2 = 2 we get\n                P02overP2 = 7.824\n                T02overT2 = 1.8\n\n                # This flow is isentropic so T01 = T02 and P01 = P02 so we can use the following ratios to solve for P2 = (P2/P02)*(P02/P01)*(P01/P1)*P1\n                P2 = (1 / P02overP2) * 1 * P01overP1 * P1\n                T2 = (1 / T02overT2) * 1 * T01overT1 * T1\n                P0 = P01overP1 * P1\n                T0 = T01overT1 * T1\n\n                print(\"The static pressure after the expansion fan is\", P2, \"atm\")\n                print(\"The temperature after the expansion fan is\", T2, \"K\")\n                print(\"The stagnation pressure is\", P0, \"atm\")\n                print(\"The stagnation temperature is\", T0, \"K\")\n                ",
            "explanation": "The challenging part of this question is understanding the properties of expansion fans, they are isentropic, so the stagnation temperature and pressure remain constant throughout.",
            "references": [
                "John D. Anderson, Christopher P. Cadou (2024) Fundamentals of Aerodynamics, McGraw-Hill."
            ]
        }
    },
    "problem14": {
        "question": "Why can't incompressible flows have shock waves?",
        "answer": "Shock waves happen when an object moves faster than the speed of sound so, there cannot be any usual reactions to variations in pressure and density which causes pressure builds up rapidly causing a wave. Now, incompressible flows are isochoric meaning that volume does not change and are characterized by having negligible changes in density. This means that incompressible flows cannot have shock waves."
    },
    "problem15": {
        "question": "Is stagnation temperature constant across an oblique shock?",
        "answer": "While it is true that the static temperature, pressure, and density increase immediately across an oblique shock. The stagnation temperature remains constant because the flow is still adiabatic, so there cannot be any heat addition."
    },
    "problem16": {
        "question": "What are the basic components of a supersonic wind tunnel and what do they do?",
        "answer": "The basic components of a supersonic wind tunnel are the nozzle, the testing or working station, the diffuser, the compressor, and a heat exchanger. The way the nozzle is shaped determines the Mach number and accelerates the air to supersonic speeds. Then the supersonic airflow goes to the working or testing station, which is where aircraft or airfoils are to be placed so the aerodynamic effects can be observed. Leaving the test section, the diffuser is where the airflow slows down and the air finally exits the wind tunnel having had pressure and velocity reduced. Due to the shock loss, air experiences a loss of stagnation pressure, the compressor helps restore that with a byproduct of increasing the temperature so there is also a heat exchanger to cool it.",
        "references": [
            "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Supersonic_wind_tunnel"
        ]
    }
}